She sacrificed all for love and others for beauty
The Countess is a drama, history, thriller film directed by Julie Delpy.
Kingdom of Hungary, 17th century.
As she gets older, powerful Countess Erzsébet Báthory (1560-1614), blinded by the passion that she feels for a
younger man, succumbs to the mad delusion that blood will keep her young and beautiful forever.
Erzsébet Báthory, played by Julie Delpy.
István Thurzó, played by Daniel Brühl.
György Thurzó, played by William Hurt.
Darvulia, played by Anamaria Marinca.
Helena, played by Maria Simon.
Dominic Vizakna, played by Sebastian Blomberg.
The Countess is a 2009 French-German historical crime thriller drama written
and directed by Julie Delpy, who also composed its score.
It stars Delpy, Daniel Brühl and William Hurt.
It is based on the life of the notorious Hungarian countess Elizabeth Báthory.
The film is the third directorial effort by Delpy, who has said of the project
that "it sounds like a gothic [story] but it's more a drama.
It's more focusing on the psychology of human beings when they're given power."
The film explores themes of hungary, biography, serial killer, older
woman younger man relationship, revisionist history.
The tone is dark and mind_bending and emotional.